# **Derek Phelps**

thederekphelps@gmail.com | 734-748-3484 | Fort Collins, CO LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/derek-phelps-76923311 | GitHub: https://github.com/dpbam Portfolio: https://dpbam.github.io/professional-portfolio-react/

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer with extensive experience working in teams and accomplishing great things for clients. Effective with communication, organization, and high-level problem-solving skills. Can combine humor and an artistically musical sense with attention to detail to be an asset to your team. I have recently completed a Full Stack Web Development certificate.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

*Frontend*: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Javascript, ES6, Jest, React, JSX, Bootstrap, Flexbox, Handlebars, Bulma, DOM Manipulation, Moment.js

*Backend*: MySQL, Sequelize, bcrypt, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, Apollo Server, Node.js, NoSQL, Web API, Third-Party API, Server Side API

#### **PROJECTS**

**Whether or Not Weather App** | https://github.com/dpbam/whether-or-not-weather-app | https://dpbam.github.io/whether-or-not-weather-app/ | Role in Project: Sole Coder

- Will provide the current weather as well as the forecast for 5 days in the future.
- Users' searches are also persistent and can be searched again upon revisiting the site.
- Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API Fetch

Shake On It | https://github.com/dpbam/shake-on-it

https://nameless-taiga-03231.herokuapp.com/ | Role in Project: Project Lead

- A bartering app for the 21st Century.
- Want a toaster, but can't afford one? Offer to mow their lawn.
- Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS (Bootstrap), JavaScript, SQL, Sequelize, bcrypt, Express

**Shop Shop** | https://github.com/dpbam/shop-shop |

https://fast-peak-42136.herokuapp.com/ Role in Project: Sole coder

- Shop Shop is a fully functional e-commerce app built with React
- Has a clean visual presentation and makes it easy to purchase, save, and checkout items.
- Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Context API, Apollo, MongoDB, Stripe

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Accenture June 2019 - March 2021

Social Media Copyright Review Agent - Austin, TX

- High level organizational and planning skills; creative and motivated
- Innovated a new way to log hip-hop artist names saving time and money for the team.

Hard Proof October 2008 - March 2021

Composer/Arranger/Trumpet - Austin, TX

• Flexible team organization, team building, robust social media management skills

#### **Royal Caribbean Cruise Lines International**

Oct 2006 - May 2006

Musical Director/Lead Trumpet - Miami, FL

- Strong performance and impressive dedication to company responsibilities and entertainment for the guests
- Promoted to Musical Director in charge of all musicians on the ship payroll, scheduling

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Texas at Austin, TX

Grad Oct. 2021

Full-Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certification

Wayne State University, Detroit, MI

Grad May 2002

Degree/Certification Attained: Bachelor of Jazz Studies